[
    {
        "front": "disjoint",
        "back": "collections of data are disjoint if no data point belongs to more than one of the collections"
    },
    {
        "front": "set",
        "back": "a set is an unordered collection of unique items"
    },
    {
        "front": "partition",
        "back": "a partition of a data set is a group of <b>disjoint</b> collections of data, such that every data point in the original data set belongs to exactly one of the collections. "
    },
    {
        "front": "statistical hypothesis",
        "back": "an explanation for phenomena observed in a data set that can be formally tested using the data"
    },
    {
        "front": "binary hypothesis test ",
        "back": "A binary hypothesis test is a statistical test that decides between two competing statistical hypotheses."
    },
    {
        "front": "null hypothesis (for multiple groups)",
        "back": "the hypothesis that the feature(s) being measured comes from the same random phenomena; any observed differences come from issues related to random sampling, such as having sets that are too small to accurately measure the true value of some summary statistic"
    },
    {
        "front": "model-based methods",
        "back": "In <I>model-based methods</I>, the data is assumed to come from some known statistical distribution. Such methods often allow the use of analytical methods."
    },
    {
        "front": "model-free methods",
        "back": "In <I>model-free methods</I>, no assumption is made about the data fitting to some statistical model.  Thus, analytical methods are usually not possible. Instead, techniques must be applied to the data itself to answer questions about the data."
    },
    {
        "front": "resampling",
        "back": "Resampling is a type of statistical simulation in which new samples are repeatedly drawn from the existing data for each of the groups under consideration, and the statistical measures being used are evaluated for each of the new sample groups. "
    },
    {
        "front": "plot legend",
        "back": "A <i>plot legend</i> is a key that shows which visual indicators (such as marker styles, line styles, and colors) correspond to which data variable."
    },
    {
        "front": "outlier",
        "back": "A value in a dataset that takes on a value that is not reasonable, based on the other values in the dataset or other domain knowledge. Outliers are often due to data entry, measurement, or unit conversion errors."
    },
    {
        "front": "mode",
        "back": "The <i>mode</i> of a data set is a value in the data set that appears most often. As there may be more than one most common value, the mode of a data set is not unique."
    },
    {
        "front": "median",
        "back": "The <i>median</i> of a data set is a value $m$ such that the number of data points that are less than $m$ is equal to the number of data points that are greater than $m$. For some data sets, there may be multiple values that satisify this criterion, so the median is not always unique."
    },
    {
        "front": "<i>average</i> (or <i>sample mean</i>) of a data set",
        "back": "The value that minimizes the squared error to the data. For a data set $d_0, d_1, \\ldots, d_{N-1}$ the average is\n \\begin{align}\n \\overline{d} = \\frac{1}{N} \\sum_{i=0}^{N-1} d_i.\n \\end{align}\n"
    }
]
